# **Antoine Soetewey**

antoinesoetewey.com

## Summary

I am a PhD candidate in statistics at UCLouvain in Belgium, within the Institute of Statistics, Biostatistics and Actuarial Sciences. My research interests focus on bio-statistical procedures applied to cancer patients. In parallel with my doctoral thesis, I am teaching assistant for several courses in statistics and probability at bachelor and master's level and I provide trainings and workshops in data science, statistics and R programming for UCLouvain's technology platform for Statistical Methodology and Computing Service. In my spare time, I write about statistics and code in R via my blog statsandr.com.

### Education

Education
<ul> <li>PhD in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium</li> <li>- Thesis: Life and health actuarial pricing: a biostatistics approach (supervisors: Prof. Catherine Legrand and Prof. Michel Denuit)</li> <li>- All publications, posters and talks available at antoinesoetewey.com/research</li> </ul>
<b>MSc in econometrics &amp; operations research</b> – Maastricht University, Netherlands - Thesis: <i>Combining professional and survey forecasts for macroeconomic data</i> (supervisor: Prof. Nalan Basturk)
MSc in economics – KULeuven, Belgium - Thesis: Negativity bias and framing effect in charity donations: a field experiment (supervisor: Prof. Jo Swinnen)
Faculty exchange – University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, USA
BSc in economics & management sciences – UCLouvain, Belgium
Teaching and consulting experience
Teaching assistant in statistics – UCLouvain, Belgium
- See all courses at antoinesoetewey.com/teaching

# 2018 – Present Private tutor in statistics and consultant in data science – Self-employed

- Private tutor for students and academics. See more information at easystat.be
- Data science consultant for professionals and companies. See more information at datanalyze.be

# Industry experience

### 2016 – 2017 Data scientist – Business & Decision, Belgium

- Involved in several projects focusing on data science and data visualization
- 2015 European public affairs intern BNP Paribas, Belgium
- 2015 **Audit intern** Deloitte, Luxembourg

# Leadership experience

### 2017 – Present International tennis chair umpire – International Tennis Federation

- Work regularly as a chair or line umpire on major tennis events across the world

### 2016 – Present Committee member – Association Francophone de Tennis, Belgium

## Technical skills & languages

### **Software**

- See all projects at antoinesoetewey.com/software

### Languages

- French (native), English (fluent), Dutch (intermediate)